Thomas P. DePatie, MSM

352.275.4217

thomas.p.depatie@gmail.com

202 S 2nd St #8, Brooklyn, NY 11211

CONSULTANT AND ORGANIZATIONAL RESEARCHER

I am an industrial-organizational psychology researcher, instructor, consultant, and current Ph.D. student at Hofstra University. My research interests center around recruitment, focusing on applicant decision-making and personorganization fit. As a consultant, I have worked on projects for clients ranging from small cities to the *Fortune* 500 regarding job analysis, competency modeling, program evaluation, 360-feedback, and organizational surveys.

✓ Research and Analysis

✓ Creative Problem Solving

✓ Excel / R / SPSS

✓ Employee Surveys/Reporting
✓ Data/Statistical Analysis

✓ Performance Management

✓ Communication

✓ Meeting/Training Facilitation

✓ Data/Statistical Analysis

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Ph.D., Applied Organizational Psychology, Hofstra University, (Hempstead, NY) Expected: May 2022 **Master of Science**, Management, University of Florida (Gainesville, FL) Earned: May 2018 **Bachelor of Science**, Psychology, Florida State University, (Tallahassee, FL) Earned: April 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

TALENT METRICS, LLC, New York, New York

2019-Present

Consulting Research Intern

- Published white paper on member location and brand reputation for the Association of Talent Development; built location heat maps and ran descriptive and inferential statistics in R, visualized data with ggplot.
- Facilitated to 50+ city employees across 4+ departments the delivery of a new competency-based performance management system built through rigorous job analysis.
- Built and delivered a virtual leadership training program directed at professionals working to navigate the COVID-19 and post-COVID-19 world.
- Analyzed pre/post-training data and generated insight report on 360-degree feedback for a set of executives at a large public teaching hospital.
- Assisted in the delivery of sexual harassment training to 200+ employees at publicly traded pharmaceutical company.
- Conducted needs analysis with key stakeholders on project regarding "The Future of Work" for an American Fortune Global 500 company.

HOFSTRA UNIVERSITY, Hempstead, New York

2018-Present

⊃ Ph.D. Researcher

- Designed and executed novel industrial-organizational psychology experiments to test job seeker decisionmaking.
- Performed descriptive and inferential statistical analysis on datasets using SPSS, R, JASP, and Jamovi; cleaned datasets in Excel.
- Collaborated with faculty and cohort to synthesize ideas into working projects; set deadlines to ensure project completion.
- Presented work at local, national, and international scientific meetings.

HOFSTRA UNIVERSITY, Hempstead, New York

2019-2020

⊃ Adjunct Instructor of Psychology

- Planned, organized, and lectured an introductory psychology course to undergraduate students (Fall 2019, Spring 2020).
- Encouraged a psychologically safe environment where students can engage in open communication and receive positive feedback and support.
- Coordinated and met with students outside of class to ensure the achievement of their goals.
- Worked with students and supervisors during the COVID-19 outbreak to ensure a smooth transition from the intended face-to-face environment to the virtual classroom.

Thomas P. DePatie, MSM

352.275.4217

thomas.p.depatie@gmail.com

202 S 2nd St #8, Brooklyn, NY 11211

HOFSTRA UNIVERSITY, Hempstead, New York

2018-2019

⊃ Institutional Research Graduate Assistant

- Managed dataset of 10,000+ students to build university factbook, structured data using PivotTables in Excel.
- Wrote and delivered 3 reports shared with the Dean of Students on student attitudes, behaviors, and expectations.
- Generated and delivered university-wide engagement surveys for program and organizational effectiveness.

PUBLICATIONS, PRESENTATIONS, & PROJECTS

DePatie, T. & Nolan, K. P. (Data Collection Phase). Social Identity Motives in Web-Based Recruitment: Does Employer Prestige Moderate the Effect of P-O Fit Feedback on Job Pursuit.

DePatie, T. & Sachdeva, A. (Manuscript Writing Phase). Coming Up Short: The Moderating Effect of Acknowledgement on Organizational Attraction.

Nolan, K.P., Farid, M., Shea, J., & **DePatie, T**. (Manuscript Writing Phase). Fit theory Elaboration: Organizational Satisfaction & Beliefs about Hiring and Firing Executive Leadership (i.e., President of the United States of America).

Weintraub, J., Cassell, D., & **DePatie, T.** (2020). Utilizing Goal-setting Nudges to Increase Flow and its Positive Outcomes at Work. A poster to be presented at The 10th European Conference on Positive Psychology (ECPP).

DePatie, T. Wolfe II, J. Islam, S. (2020) Understanding ATD Long Island Members and Events: Location and Brand Reputation Analysis. A white paper written for the Association for Talent Development Long Island.

DePatie, T., Islam, S., & Defina, C. (2020) Coffee Shops Use of Instagram: A Consumer Psychology View of Entrepreneurship. A poster to be presented at the Association for Psychological Science Conference in May 2020.

Lyew, A., Islam, S., & **DePatie, T**. (2020) Diversity in Images in Consulting Firm White Papers: A Qualitative Review. A poster to be presented at the Association for Psychological Science Conference in May 2020.

Wolfe, J. Islam, S., & **DePatie, T**. (2020) Corporate Reputation's Impact on Event Attendance: A Natural Experiment. A poster to be presented at the Association for Psychological Science Conference in May 2020.

Di Cecco, P., **DePatie, T**., La Sala, S., Lobo, S., Schmidt, G., & Islam, S. (2019) How Leaders Tweet: An Exploratory Analysis of Entrepreneurial Leader Tweets. A poster to be presented at the Celebration for Scholarship Farmingdale State College on November 5th, 2019.

ADDITIONAL DATA

- Technical Skills: MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook), SPSS, R, JASP, Jamovi
- Statistical Methods: Descriptive Statistics, Inferential Statistics (t-test, ANOVA, correlation analysis, regression)
- Society for Judgement Research Methods: Survey Research, (Quasi-)experimental designs
- PhDs in Applied Organizational Psychology, Vice-President
- Society for Industrial and Organizational Psychology, Student Affiliate
- New York Metropolitan Association of Applied Psychology (METRO), Student Member
- University of Florida (UF) Alumni Association, Life Member